<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Teaching on Matt Richards - Blog</title><link>https://m-richards.github.io/categories/teaching/</link><description>Recent content in Teaching on Matt Richards - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 21:01:14 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://m-richards.github.io/categories/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Roaming</title><link>https://m-richards.github.io/post/roaming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 21:01:14 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://m-richards.github.io/post/roaming/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been on an overseas trip, and it seems without fail that the concept of mobile roaming charges causes confusion and headaches for me (or perhaps more specifically my travelling companions). This is a short post to crystallise what I&amp;rsquo;ve re-learnt and to have something to refer to
There are a few related concepts at play:
Roaming - whether you can do anything (make calls, send messages, emergency calls, access the internet) with your phone using cellular data.</description></item><item><title>Remote Access with SSH Quickstart</title><link>https://m-richards.github.io/post/using_ssh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 20:20:25 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://m-richards.github.io/post/using_ssh/</guid><description>This is a post that I hope to be able to point someone to the next time I&amp;rsquo;m teaching someone how to ssh into a machine. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are better posts out there on this, but I want this to be terse and pragmatic, without a whole lot of backstory.
So you want to log into a remote server, either a local server computer or on the cloud. Usually, I&amp;rsquo;m teaching a windows speaking audience, where I personally use WSL for ssh, but these instructions are also geared to powershell.</description></item><item><title>Setting up a pandas/main environment for GeoPandas</title><link>https://m-richards.github.io/post/geopandas_dev_env/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 18:05:38 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://m-richards.github.io/post/geopandas_dev_env/</guid><description>Although it&amp;rsquo;s not something I tend to advertise very often, I&amp;rsquo;m a maintainer for GeoPandas which is the de-facto standard tool for tabular geospatial analysis in Python. My contributions here wax and wane here with the amount of free time and mental space I have to volunteer. As part of this, we keep the software in sync with developments in pandas, and our CI tests against pandas/main. From time to time (more frequently with the upcoming pandas 2.</description></item></channel></rss>